<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jincheng Li</title>
    <link>http://jincheng.li/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Jincheng Li</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Apr 2018 14:56:57 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://jincheng.li/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>What Really Goes on in a Computer</title>
      <link>http://jincheng.li/post/basic-comp-arch/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Apr 2018 14:56:57 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jincheng.li/post/basic-comp-arch/</guid>
      <description>I wanted to start a series of posts on how the Linux operating system works, partially inspired by linux-insides, but instead of covering the entire operating system which is way too much work for my lazy ass, I&amp;rsquo;ll just focus on several aspects of the OS which I find interesting and may have taken me more time to grasp compared to other things.
My motivation for doing this is mainly to learn more about Linux.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PostgreSQL Query Optimization</title>
      <link>http://jincheng.li/post/postgres-query-opt/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jincheng.li/post/postgres-query-opt/</guid>
      <description>The other day I saw a tweet about blog posts it would be great to see, and one of them was &amp;ldquo;inside PostgreSQL: how a join works internally, what makes it fast&amp;rdquo;. Coincidentally, I&amp;rsquo;m taking a course on database system implementation, and I thought this would be a great way to study for my midterm! Of course, by the time I&amp;rsquo;ve finished this post, the midterm is long gone, but it was still a great incentive for me to start writing :)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why This Blog</title>
      <link>http://jincheng.li/post/first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jincheng.li/post/first-post/</guid>
      <description>I originally started this blog as a graduate student while I was at Columbia, in the hopes of putting my spare time to better use than playing video games. Now I just use it as a reason for me to do some research into things I never dedicate enough time to understand, and hopefully benefit whoever stumbles upon it.
Also in case you&amp;rsquo;re wondering, it&amp;rsquo;s unbelievably easy to spin up something like this.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>