<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Jincheng Li</title>
    <link>http://jincheng.li/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Jincheng Li</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Apr 2018 14:56:57 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://jincheng.li/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Computer Architecture 101</title>
      <link>http://jincheng.li/post/basic-comp-arch/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Apr 2018 14:56:57 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jincheng.li/post/basic-comp-arch/</guid>
      <description>A review of basic computer architecture follows, partially inspired by linux-insides.
Von Neumann Machines Computers today roughly follow the von Neumann architecture as shown above, with three major components &amp;ndash; CPU, I/O devices, and memory &amp;ndash; connected over buses (wires). The computer works as the CPU executes instructions that either read/write to memory, or interact with I/O devices.
From the software perspective, this model is pretty much all there is to a computer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enforcing Email Frequency Caps</title>
      <link>http://jincheng.li/post/email-frequency-cap/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Mar 2018 16:15:24 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jincheng.li/post/email-frequency-cap/</guid>
      <description>Enough with the Spamming: Enforcing Email Frequency Caps This is something I did at work, posted to Medium. It talks about challenges involved in preventing our services from sending too many emails to the same address quickly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PostgreSQL Query Optimization</title>
      <link>http://jincheng.li/post/postgres-query-opt/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jincheng.li/post/postgres-query-opt/</guid>
      <description>This post gives a high-level explanation of Postgres query optimization. It assumes basic familiarity with relational databases and SQL queries. Having some knowledge in query optimization helps, but is not necessary.
Background PostgreSQL, or Postgres, is an open-source object-relational database management system. It has gone through around 30 years of development, has a ton of features, and is very popular within the database community. This post will focus on its query optimization routines, particularly how it optimizes join queries, but if you&amp;rsquo;re curious, you should definitely check out the source code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About This Blog</title>
      <link>http://jincheng.li/post/first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jincheng.li/post/first-post/</guid>
      <description>I originally started this blog as a graduate student at Columbia, in the hopes of putting my spare time to better use. Now it&amp;rsquo;s just a rarely updated dumping ground of half-written articles :)
This site is powered by Hugo and Github Pages. The theme is Hugo Xmin.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>